In webpack, there are two ways you can set the environment mode.
在 webpack 中 有两种方法可以设置环境模式
You can either do it through the CLI tool and in
可以通过在终端使用 CLI 工具
your terminal or you can actually set that in the webpack.config.
也可以在 webpack 配置文件中进行设置
If you need to run it through the terminal, that's totally fine.
如果你需要通过终端运行 完全没问题
In this course we're going to teach you how to actually
不过在本课程中 我们将教你如何
embed it into your config because we're going to
将模式嵌入到配置中
follow the webpack documentation and create
我们会按照 webpack 文档
two different config files for our production and development modes.
创建两个不同的配置文件 分别用于生产和开发模式
Inside of your webpack config file,
在 webpack 配置文件中
you can add a mode flag by adding a mode attribute to the module exports.
你可以在 module.exports 添加一个模式属性来标识模式
You can have production here.
可以在这里设置生产
You can put development here.
可以将开发放在这里
Many professional apps are going to have more than two modes.
很多专业应用都包含两种以上的模式
So you'll probably have a testing mode and who knows what other modes but the cool thing
所以你很可能还有一个测试模式或其他不为人知的模式
about webpack modes is that they're fairly flexible and you
不过 webpack 模式相当灵活
can create them to be whatever you need them to be.
可以创建任何你需要的模式
Every app though has the option for development and production.
不过每个应用都会有开发和生产环境
So those are the two that we're going to stick with in this course.
所以 我们在本课程中也专注于这两种模式
In your webpack file,
在你的 webpack 文件中
you could create conditionals that check for a production or development mode.
你可以创建条件语句来检测当前处于生产还是开发模式
But that can get a little bit messy and you end up with a lot of
但这可能会导致混乱 最终会得到很多
logic that's similar but different and right on top of each other.
极其相似 彼此重叠但又不完全相同的逻辑
So in order to keep our webpack configs just a little bit cleaner,
因此 为了使 webpack 配置更加简洁
we're going to go ahead and create a second webpack config file.
我们会创建第二个 webpack 配置文件
So in the root of your project and
在项目的根目录下
exactly the same place as your current webpack config file is,
准确来说是在和当前 webpack 配置文件同级目录中
go ahead and make a new file and call it production.
创建一个新文件 区分命名为生产相关
So webpack.prod.js for instance.
例如 webpack.prod.js
So now that we have this new web pack prod file,
现在有了新的 webpack.prod 配置文件
we just need to rename our webpack config file to become the dev file.
只需要将 webpack.config 文件重命名为开发文件即可
So in your text editor,
在文本编辑器中
just rename the file and I'm going to rename mine to be dev.
重命名这个文件 我将重命名为 dev
For now I'm just going to copy the contents of my dev file into the prod file.
现在 将 dev 文件的内容复制到 prod 文件中
We're going to totally change the production file eventually.
虽然最终我们会彻底修改生产配置文件
But just so we can have something there that will
现在这样做是为了其中能有些内容
run the moment, we're going to keep that thing.
运行起来 所以先使用这些内容
So now that we have a dev and a prod file,
现在有了一个 dev 和一个 prod 文件
we need to actually be able to run these.
我们需要能够运行它们
But currently our package.json has a very generic build command and instead,
但是当前 package.json 中有一个通用的构建命令
we need a build command that's going to reference the dev and prod files respectively.
现在需要分别引用 dev 和 prod 文件的构建命令
So what I'm going to do is replace this with some specialized scripts.
所以我要替换为专用命令
We now have a build-prod and a build-dev and they
现在有一个 build-prod 和一个 build-dev 命令
respectively go to webpack prod and prod.
分别对应 webpack prod 和 dev 配置
So now that these two files are pointing to the correct files, there we go.
现在这两个命令都已指向正确的配置文件了
them separately and that's really where webpack gives us a lot of flexibility,
我们可以分别运行 而这正是 webpack 带来的灵活性
is I can pretend to be in production mode and
我可以模拟生产模式
all it takes is me just running a slightly different command which is awesome.
只需要运行一个稍微不同的命令就可以了 非常棒